Mss.B.G78 Mss.B.G78
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence
  - Letter to Nehemiah Cleaveland, June 21, 1851; B G78.4; 10x7-3/4; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
    Brooklyn, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Wishes to start a school for young ladies and wonders if he will teach moral philosophy and English literature.
  - Letter to Mr. James, Jan. 25, 1854; B G78.5; 7x4-1/2; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
    Washington, A.L.S. 3p. Cannot possibly visit him in Philadelphia at noon, for they will not arrive there until around 2:00 P.M.
  - Letter to [Thomas Potts] James, April 27, 1856; B G78.6; 7x4-1/2; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
    Cambridge, A.L.S. 2p. Finances. Owes Fendler a letter.
  - Letter to Messrs. Putnam, July 15, 1855; B G78.7; 7-3/4x5; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. and end. Concerning proof for his Flora of North America.
  - Letter to Mr. Delvin, Dec. 9, 1887; B G78.8; 8x5; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. Recommends article by N. B. Ward on raising plants indoors.
  - Letter to [Noah?] Porter, May 14, 1849; B G78.9; 7x4-1/2; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 2p. Introduces Dr. Alexander, of England, who comes botanizing in the U.S.
  - Letter to General Breck, June 8, 1871; B G78.10; 7x4-1/2; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 4p. Concerning the possible purchase of a rare botanical work.
  - Letter to [Cora E. Dike], March 22, [1883]; B G78.11; 7x4-1/2; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
    A.L.S. 1p. Draft. Answers her inquiry on botany. On same sheet as C.E.Dike to Gray; March 7, 1883.
  - Letter to [Asa] Gray, March 7, 1883; B G78.11; 7x4-1/2; Dike, Cora E
    Stoneham, Mass., A.L.S. 3p. Botanical questions. On same sheet is draft of Gray to C. E. Dike; [March] 22, [1883].
  - Letter to [Edward Greely?] Loring, Feb. 10, 1865; B G78.12; 10x8; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 4p. Concerning Greenough's memorial for lowering requirements for students at Harvard.
  - Letter to W[illia]m S. Vaux, April 4, 1861; B G78.13; 10x8; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
    Boston, Mass., A.L.S. 3p. Concerning misshipment of geological books to the American Academy of Arts and Sciences rather than the Academy of Natural Sciences in Philadelphia.
  - Letter to Dr. Mckennan, May 15, 1886; B G78.14; 8-1/2x5; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. The momorial to his uncle is to be printed by the American Academy of Arts and Sciences.
  - Letter to B. W. Austin, May 22, 1886; B G78.15; 7x4-1/2; Gray, Asa, 1810-1888
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for notification of election to the Northwestern Literary and Historical Society at Sioux City, Iowa.